- Welcome to our training on how to prevent or resolve
product detail page policy violations.
Amazon's product detail page policies
help ensure customers have a clear
and consistent buying experience.
In this video, we'll share an overview of these policies
and tips to help you comply with them.
-
We'll also share resources you can use
to learn more about specific error codes you've received
while creating offers.
Amazon's product detail page policies
require all sellers to comply with a set of guidelines.
The majority of these guidelines relate to four requirements.
Each product detail page must.
One, cover a single unique item.
Two, comply with relevant style guides,
which include formatting and style rules,
character limits, and prohibited information and images.
Three, exclude false or promotional content or actions
like cross promotion of a product
or the creation of a new product detail page
for a product that's already listed in Amazon's catalog.
And four, only be updated with edits
that make the page better
or more accurately describe the product.
-
Keep in mind that this video is not a replacement
for closely reviewing Amazon's product detail page policies
or category specific guidelines.
It's important to familiarize yourself with them
to help you avoid interruptions to your business.
Search product detail page rules in Seller Central
for more information.
Now let's review these four requirements in more detail.
Beginning with how to ensure each product detail page
covers a single unique item.
How you list products depends on whether or not
they're already being sold in the Amazon store.
You'll either create an offer for an existing product
or create a new listing
for one that isn't already in the Amazon catalog.
If you're new to selling in the Amazon store,
pause here and complete the list product video series
in Seller University.
You'll get step-by-step instructions
for each part of the listing process
and learn how to manage product IDs and exemptions.
If you've already listed products,
you're likely familiar with variations.
If you have products that are similar in nature
but differ from each other by a few factors
like color and size,
you won't create new listings for each item.
Instead, you can create a single variation family
for these products.
When your product has variations,
it has a parent ASIN and one or more child ASINs
or child variations.
For example, if you sell a shirt in different sizes
and colors, the shirt represents the parent ASIN.
The shirt's variations, such as blue and medium,
represent child ASINs.
You can violate Amazon's product detail page policy
if you misuse variations.
Remember to ensure only one unique product
is featured on each page and only use valid variations.
To determine whether or not they're valid,
ask yourself these questions.
Are the products fundamentally the same?
Could the products share the same title?
Do the products vary only in a few specific ways
that don't alter the core essence and nature of the item
like color and size?
Would customers expect to find these products together
on a single product detail page?
Let's use these criteria to evaluate two examples.
In the first example,
a seller is listing a cell phone charging cable
and a portable charger.
Should they use a variation family
or list these products separately?
While the items are related,
they're not the same product
and shouldn't be listed on the same product detail page.
Another seller is listing a single brand
and type of dog treats,
but in different quantities and flavors,
are the products closely related enough
to be considered child products?
The answer is yes,
meaning the items should be listed as variations
on the same product detail page.
For more information on variations,
search variation relationships overview
and ASIN creation policy in Seller Central.
Let's move on to the second guideline,
comply with relevant style and information guides.
You can find general rules that apply to all products
in the Amazon Services Quick Start Style Guide,
which you'll find on the product detail page rules help page.
Certain product categories have extra style guidelines,
which you can reference on that same help page.
Certain guidelines aren't obvious.
For example, formatting rules or character limits
can be difficult to notice by only skimming
an existing page.
Closely review the style guides
and take note of any help text while creating an offer.
There are also guidelines for the types of content
you include on a product detail page.
In general,
make sure you accurately describe and categorize products.
Never infringe upon the intellectual property rights
of any third party.
Avoid including inappropriate content,
links, contact information or requests for reviews.
This brings us to our third guideline.
Avoid false or promotional content.
A few examples include requesting positive customer reviews,
highlighting specific reviews, quotes or testimonials,
linking to other websites where customers can place orders
or adding your watermark to images or videos.
Finally, you can also violate Amazon policies
if you create a new product detail page
when one already exists for that same product.
Keep this in mind before you create a new offer.
As a reminder,
you can verify whether one already exists
by searching for the product
on the product adding page in Seller Central.
To get there, open the Seller Central main menu,
hover over catalog and click Add Products.
But after you list a product,
you may be able to suggest an edit
to improve an existing product detail page's accuracy.
Since these pages are shared with other sellers,
we have guardrails in place.
For example, your ability to suggest an edit
depends on your relationship with the product.
If a product is enrolled in Amazon brand registry,
only three types of sellers can suggest edits.
The original rights owner who enrolled the brand,
other sellers verified as internal to the brand,
and resellers who are associated with the brand
and approved to sell its products.
If the product isn't part of a brand enrolled
in brand registry,
the seller who created the product detail page
and all sellers who have matched offers can suggest edits.
To learn how to suggest edits,
complete the Suggest an edit
to a product detail page training in Seller University.
Keep in mind that Amazon policies
don't allow incorrect detail page modifications.
Incorrect modifications are any changes
that cause the product to become inaccurately described
or less accurately described than it was before the change.
We only allow updates that improve the detail page.
This can include changes
like improving the accuracy of the content,
making the content grammatically correct,
or removing content that violates Amazon policies.
Let's review an example of an Amazon seller
who is in violation of Amazon's product detail page policies
because they incorrectly modified a page.
A seller has gained the appropriate documentation
and approvals to sell a branded product in the Amazon store.
They successfully listed the product,
but returned to the product detail page
to make some changes.
They wanted to promote their own company's name to customers,
so they added it to the ASIN title and product description.
In this example,
the seller failed to comply with Amazon's policies.
Even the best intentioned sellers can make mistakes
when listing products and creating offers.
Amazon uses error messages to prevent incorrect information
from being displayed in the Amazon store.
You'll receive an error if you don't meet Amazon's requirements
for a properly formatted entry.
For example, we won't include your contribution
if you attempt to create an offer
with a description that exceeds 1,000 characters,
but your offer will still be available.
You can browse a list of error messages
along with their definitions and suggested solutions
in Seller Central.
Search error code explanations
and locate the error code in the all articles list.
For more information on how to create
effective and compliant product detail pages,
watch the Intro to Product Detail pages
and best practices for product detail pages,
videos in Seller University.
They'll help you comply with Amazon standards and style guides.
This concludes our training on how to prevent
or resolve product detail page policy violations.
Continue to the next video in this series
to learn how to avoid making other common listing errors.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.